

#### **Hakan KARASU**

Nationality: Turkish Date of birth: 04/04/1997 Gender: Male

**Phone number:** (+82) 010-8059-2829

**Email address:** hakankarasu97@hotmail.com

■ Website: https://hakankarasu.github.io/

Adress: Seoul/KOREA

Adress Home: Inkilap Mah Umraniye / Istanbul / TURKIYE

#### **About Me**

Hey! It is **Hakan KARASU, and** I am a **Mechanical Engineer** at the Korea Institute of Science and Technology (KIST) in Korea. I am also pursuing a master's degree at the University of Science and Technology (UST). Currently, My research focuses on the application of deep learning (CBAM+GradCAM) on the electrochemical system. I enjoy machine learning, deep learning, its application as well as robot operating systems, and learning new things daily. I am passionate about developing models that can solve real-life problems I am constantly learning new things to improve my skills.

#### **Work Experience**

Korea Institute of Science and Technology (KIST) [ 01/09/2021 - Current ]

City: Seoul Country: Korea

My research project is focused on developing model that can not only predict the performance of electrochemical system also the underlying cause of catalyst degradation through explainable artificial intelligence.

(1D Convolutional Block Attention Module(CBAM)+GRADCAM(XAI)

Hand-crafted machine learning models

Note: This project is mostly based on data-driven

Supervisor: Prof. Ung LEE (Principle Researcher, Clean Energy Research Center, KIST)

**Demonstration of Omni-Directional Mobile robot in KIST** 

Supervisor: Senior Researcher Center for Healthcare Robotics (Soonkyum Kim)

### Research Assistant (Intern)

Korea Institute of Science and Technology [ 23/09/2020 - 31/08/2021]

City: Seoul

Country: South Korea

### Research Assistant (Intern)

**Center of Flow Simulation** [ 09/2017 - 31/08/2018]

**City:** Dusseldorf **Country:** Germany

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Ing, Ali Cemal Benim (Head of Center of Flow Simulation)Supervisor:

Dr. Bjorn Pfeiffelmann

I worked within two research and development projects namely on "Biomass Combustion - Improving the energetic performance of a wood chips firing furnace" (Python) and "Improving the aeroacoustics of small axial wind turbines (Computational Fluid Dynamics)".

Korea Institute of Science and Technology [ 06/01/2020 - 31/08/2020]Throughout

these projects, I used:

- Python
- Linux
- C++
- Solid-WORKS (for prototype case design)
- ROS (Robot Operating System-Navigation) (Real-Time Robot Navigation implemented at KIST)
- Fluent(ANSYS)
- ICEM-CFD

#### **Education and Training**

#### **Umraniye High School**

Address: Umraniye/Istanbul Website:

İSTANBUL / ÜMRANİYE - Ümraniye

Merkez Anadolu Lisesi (meb.k12.tr)

#### **Bachelor Degree Mechanical Engineer**

Sakarya University / Sakarya /Turkey [ 09/2015 -09/2019]

Address: Sakarya (Turkey) Website:

www.sakarya.edu.trFinal grade:

3.41/4

### Master Degree in Division of Energy & Environment Technology

**University of Science and Technology** [ 09/2021 –Current]

Address: Daejeon /Korea Website:

https://www.ust.ac.krFinal grade:

4.2/4.5

### **Language Skills**

Mother tongue(s): Turkish

### Other language(s):

English Korean German

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 Topic 1 Level 2 Beginner

### AI / Machine Learning / Deep Learning

Python / Tensorflow / PyTorch / ONNX & ONNX Runtime / MATLAB / Julia / Pandas Numpy Scikit-learn Scipy libraries

### **Robot Operating System**

Ros

#### **Prototyping Products**

SolidWorks

#### **Others**

/ Real-time Linux, Gazebo (ROS)

## **Conferences and Seminars**

# Implementation of deep learning on the electrochemical systems

[ KICHE / Oral Presentation ] [10/2021] [Gwangju/KOREA]

Link: www.kiche.or.kr

### Conference

[ Kiche /Oral Presentation ] [10/2022] [BUSAN KOREA]

Link: www.kiche.or.kr

# **Honours and Awards from Engineering Faculty**

Sakarya University Engineering Faculty [ 2019 ]

I have ranked fourth among the faculty of engineering students graduating in 2019.

## **Scholarship**

Mevlana Scholarship [best student award in faculty]

## **Hobbies and Interests**

Basketball, football, hobby electronics, 3D printing, cooking, theater and books.

### Certificates

AI (Artificial Intelligence) Education Certification (UST)

## **Paper Publication**

Ongoing